SAMUEL ALBI PULO S

081290156204 | samuelalbi09@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-albi-pulo-s-084392272/ | https://rb.gy/gejr4w

Bekasi City, West Java

Fourth semester Informatics Engineering student at Del Institute of Technology who has an interest in developing skills in the developer field, especially Frontend Developer, Backend Developer, and Full-Stack Developer. Has experience in project assignments and being a teaching assistant in the field of database management systems that perform several development methods, including web application development and API development. Have experience in performing several development methods, including proficiency in using SQL Query, Normalization, and MS. Access. I have expertise in creating clean program code to ensure programs are easy to develop and easy to read, able to communicate well, and can work in a team. I can operate several development tools, such as Visual Studio Code, Postman, and XAMPP. Extensive experience and expertise can make a positive contribution to the company's bottom line.

Education Level

Del Institute of Technology - Laguboti, Indonesia

Aug 2022 - Present

Diploma 3 Information Technology in Vocational Faculty, GPA: 3.33/4.00

· Assistant Lecturer in Community Service at SMKN 2 Balige

Krida Nusantara Integrated High School - Bandung, West Java

Jul 2019 - May 2022

Natural Science (IPA)

· Participate in a basic program which is carried out for 3 months to train the leadership attitudes of each student

Professional Experience & Organization

Google Developer Student Clubs IT Del - Laguboti, Indonesia

Oct 2023 - Present

Member

- · Participated in educational programs held by Google Developer Student Clubs Center
- Reached the final stage of the Hackfest competition organized by Google Developer Students Clubs.

Del Institute of Technology - Laguboti, Indonesia

Aug 2023 - Jun 2024

Student Leadership Program

- Guided and provided assistance to new students during their first year on campus.
- Helped new students adjust to the campus environment by providing advice
- Took care of 14 new student siblings in one foster family

Del Institute of Technology - Laguboti, Indonesia

Feb 2024 - May 2024

Teaching Assistant

- Managed a Database Management System using MySQL.
- · Assisted in the Introduction to Database course.
- Taught more than 50 students.
- · Created guidelines documentation for the students.
- · Collaborated with a team of other Teaching Assistants and Lecturers of the database introduction course.
- Created questions for assignments and exams both questions and make videos to students at the end of each second learning session.
- Checked the results of assignments and exams both questions and making videos that have been done by students

Project

Final Project 2 - Del Clinic App (Link Project)

Feb 2024 - Jun 2024

Frontend, Backend and Project Manager

- Collaborated with team members to analyze requirements and translate them into technical specifications.
- Developed a mobile-based Information System Del Clinic App using the Flutter framework.
- Created a website-based application for Admin using the React JS framework.
- Built an API-based backend using Golang Fiber and Golang Object Relation Model.
- Managed the Database Management System with MySQL.
- Manage the team by monitoring that all application implementations are in line with the design.

Distributed Programming Final Project - Del Clinic Microservice API (Link Project)

Apr 2024 - Jun 2024

Backend and Project Manager

- Collaborated with team members to analyze requirements and translate them into technical specifications.
- Developed Microservice API-based solutions using Golang Fiber and Golang Object Relation Model.
- Utilized Postman for API testing and MySQL for Database Management System.
- Wrote clean, efficient, and maintainable code following project requirements and coding standards

.

Frontend, Backend and Project Manager

- · Conducted and collected data requirements for the Lumban Binanga Village Website.
- Created technical documents for website design.
- Built the system using the Laravel framework.
- Create 8 sequence diagrams, Business Process Models and Notations, entity relationship diagrams, class diagrams, use case diagrams, and use case scenarios from the previously conducted requirements gathering.

Website Development 1 - Huta Siallagan Wesbite (Link Project)

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

Frontend

- Performed and collected data requirements for the Huta Siallagan Website.
- · Created technical documents for website design.
- Developed the program using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript ES12.

Competition

Google Hackfest Competition (Certificate)

Feb 2024 - Jun 2024

Hustler

- Designing a solution for the 17 sustainable development group, which emphasizes zero hunger and quality education in the system to be designed.
- Designing how to make the application relate to the intended community by applying the business model canvas to the designed application.
- Reached final stage out of 150+ teams by developing innovative tech solution

Himatif Coding Competition (Certificate)

Jul 2023

Team Leader

- Won 3rd place at the Himatif Coding Day, which consisted of more than 20 groups of 3 people.
- Solved more than 5 problems ranging from easy to difficult levels using the c language on the HackerRank website

Technical Skill

- Programming languages: Java, GO, C, C#, PHP, SQL, JavaScript, Kotlin, Dart.
- Tools Code Editor & Modelling: Visual Studio Code, StarUML, Bizagi, PowerDesigner, dan Visual Paradigm, Postman
- Tools Designs: Figma, Canva, Adobe Photoshop
- Software Development Life Cycle: Agile, Waterfall, Scrum and V-model
- Version Control : Github
- Documentation: Google Docs, Google Sheets, Google Slides
- Frontend Framework: React JS
- Backend Framework: Golang Fiber, Golang Object Relation Model.
- Fullstack Framework: Laravel, ASP.NET
- CSS Framework: Tailwind CSS 3.0 and Bootstrap 5.2.3
- · Architectural Patterns: Object Oriented Programming (OOP), and Model View Controller (MVC)
- JavaScript Object Notation (JSON)
- HyperText Markup Language 5 (HTML5)
- · Cascading Style Sheets 3 (CSS3)
- · Data Structure Algorithms
- Microservices / Distributed Programming
- Language : Indonesia (Native), and English (Proficient)

Statement of Purpose

All the above activities have helped me in many ways so I

- Ability to develop Web Application
- · Critical Thinking
- Ability to develop API: RESTful API & Microservice API
- · Adaptable easily in new place and condition
- · Ability to solve problems
- · Love to learn new things
- · Ability to work in a team and have responsibility
- · Ability to communicate and work well with teams
- · Ability to propose innovative and creative ideas

I hereby certify that the information provided is true.